Lowe, Adolf; Papers ger022
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Correspondence, 1928-1995; 1983-1990; 2; 2 cubic ft.
  - Correspondence with colleagues, friends, 2.3
    - Vogelstein, Theodor M., 1950-1951 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 11)
    - von Eynern, Gert, 1962-1963; 1984 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 12)
    - Vuagnat, Fréderique, 1983-1984 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 13)
    - Waldman, Frederic (Fritz), 1986 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 14)
    - Wallace, Edith, 1983-1990 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 15)
    - Waubke, M., 1984-1989 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 16)
    - Weber, Alfred, 1950 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 17)
    - White, Howard, 1951 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 18)
    - Wunderlich, [Frieda?], 1950 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 19)
    - Correspondence Concerning "Notes on University Education", 1940 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 20)
    - Correspondence Concerning "On Economic Knowledge", 1965-1971 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 21)
  - Correspondence with publishers, 2.4
    - Cambridge University Press, 1976; 1983 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 22)
    - Insel Verlag, 1987-1988 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 23)
    - M. E. Sharpe, Inc., 1979-1991 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 24)
    - New York University Press, concerning "Essays in Political Economics", 1987 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 25)
    - Praeger (Greenwood Press), 1986-1990 (Box 3 (2-Correspondence), Folder 26)
- Scholarly Writings, 1932-ca. 1990; 3; 0.90 cubic ft.
  This series contains many of Lowe's articles, book manuscripts, and notes for lectures delivered before various academic and civic groups. Most of these materials were written while Lowe lived in Great Britain and the United States, but the earliest and most recent materials were produced while he resided in Germany.
  Arranged chronologically within subseries.
  - Subseries 1: Articles, Reviews, and Books, 1932-ca. 1990; 3.1; 0.60 cubic ft.
    This sub-series contains some of Lowe's published and unpublished studies of economics, sociology, and current affairs. Highlights include a lengthy essay written in the form of a letter to his close friend Hans Jonas, unpublished materials that he apparently drafted while writing Has Freedom a Future?, and a complete typescript of the book itself.
    - "Über den Sinn und die Grenzen verstehender Nationalökonomie" (published), 1932 (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 27)
    - "The Social Productivity of Technical Improvements" (published), 1937 (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 28)
    - Review of Middleton Murry, In Defence of Democracy (unpublished TS), and letter, 1938 (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 29)
    - "The Technique of Economic Mobilization" (unpublished TS), 1939 (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 30)
    - "On the Introduction of the Social Sciences... at the Hebrew University" (unpublished TS), 1939 (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 31)
    - "Nationalism and the Economic Order" (published), 1939? (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 32)
    - "Social Transformation and the War" (published letter), 1940 (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 33)
    - Newspaper Articles on Germany, Britain, and the Second World War (published), 1940 (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 34)
    - Analysis of British Economic Problems (unpublished TS), 1940? (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 35)
    - "A Reconsideration of the Laws of Supply and Demand" (published), 1942 (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 36)
    - "The Study of World Affairs" (published), 1943 (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 37)
    - "The Trend of World Economics" (published), 1944 (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 38)
    - "To A German Friend Behind Bars" (unpublished MS), 1950 (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 39)
    - "On the Mechanistic Approach in Economics" (published), 1951 (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 40)
    - "Rejoinder [to James Parsons]" (published), 1952 (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 41)
    - Preface to the Japanese edition of On Economic Knowledge (unpublished TS), 1953 (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 42)
    - "The Classical Theory of Economic Growth" (published), 1954 (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 43)
    - "Wirtschaftstheorie --Der nächste Schritt" (published), 1959 (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 44)
    - "Über eine dritte Kraft" (published), 1961 (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 45)
    - "S Is Not Yet P: A Question Put to Ernst Bloch" (unpublished TS), 1964-1965 (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 46)
    - Letter to Hans Jonas, 1966 (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 47)
      (unpublished typescripts) and notes.
    - "The Normative Roots of Economic Value" (unpublished TS), 1967 (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 48)
    - "Vorbemerkung" (unpublished TS), 1968 (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 49)
    - "Die Leiden des alten Atlas: Ernst Bloch zum fuenfundachtigen Gerburtstag" (unpublished TS), ca. 1970 (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 50)
    - "Personal Freedom in an Era of Social Engineering" (unpublished TS), and "Comments on Middleton Murry's Paper" (unpublished TS), 1973 (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 51)
    - "Technical Profits" (unpublished TS), 1977 (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 52)
    - "Über das Dunkel des gelebten Augenblicks", 1978? (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 53)
    - "Atlas: The Burden of the Man Without Chains" (unpublished TS), ca. 1980 (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 54)
    - "To Rid Loans of the Inflation Risk" (published letter), 1981 (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 55)
    - "The Specter of Technological Unemployment" (unpublished TS), 1987? (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 56)
    - Has Freedom a Future? (unpublished TS), 1987 (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 57)
    - "Freiheit und Ordnung" (unpublished TS), 1988? (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 58)
    - Lecture Notes on Simmel's "Philosophie der Griechen", Undated (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 59)
      (unpublished manuscript), 1913, and Transcript (unpublished typescript), ca. 1990.
    - "Technological Unemployment Reexamined" (published), Undated (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 60)
    - "The Paradigms of Positive Economics" (unpublished TS) and "The Marxian Paradigm" (unpublished TS), Undated (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 61)
    - "The Economic Mechanism" (unpublished TS), Undated (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 62)
    - "Adam Smith's System of Equilibrium Growth" (published), Undated (Box 3 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 63)
  - Subseries 2: Lectures, 1932-1983; 3.2; 0.30 cubic ft.
    This sub-series consists of notes for lectures that Lowe delivered at various academic institutions and before various community groups. Some of these speeches were given before the New School's Study Group on Germany (1942-43) and its General Seminar, an interdisciplinary forum at which faculty members discussed their work.
    - "The Future of English Democracy and the Jews" (unpublished MS), 1932 (Box 4 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 1)
    - "Der Sozialismus ist heute... !" (unpublished MS), 1933 (Box 4 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 2)
    - "Sind die Denken andersartig?" (unpublished MS), ca. 1935 (Box 4 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 3)
    - "The University in the Modern World" (unpublished MS), 1938 (Box 4 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 4)
    - "Democracy and Freedom" (unpublished MS), 1939 (Box 4 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 5)
    - "What Is It All About?", 1940; (unpublished manuscript) and clipping (Box 4 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 6)
    - "National Council of Women" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 7)
    - "Self-Help" (unpublished MS), 1942 (Box 4 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 8)
    - "Characteristic Facts and Events Relating to German History before 1500" (unpublished MS), 1942 (Box 4 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 9)
    - "Sind die Denken andersartig?" (unpublished MS), 1942 (Box 4 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 10)
    - "Higher Education in U.S". (unpublished MS), 1944 (Box 4 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 11)
    - "Economic Planning and Common Sense" (unpublished MS), 1945 (Box 4 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 12)
    - "What Can We Do? [1]" (unpublished MS), 1946 (Box 4 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 13)
    - "What Can We Do? [2]" (unpublished MS), 1946 (Box 4 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 14)
    - "Integration in the Social Sciences?" (unpublished MS), 1950 (Box 4 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 15)
    - "America's Problem in the World Today: What It Is" (unpublished TS), 1952 (Box 4 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 16)
    - "America's Problem in the World Today: What It Should Be" (unpublished TS), 1952 (Box 4 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 17)
    - "Europe Revisited" (unpublished MS), 1952 (Box 4 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 18)
    - "Europe in the Old Order of World Affairs" (unpublished MS), 1952 (Box 4 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 19)
    - "The Meaning of the Contemporary Crisis" (unpublished MS), 1952 (Box 4 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 20)
    - "The Next Step" (unpublished MS), 1952 (Box 4 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 21)
    - "Cooperation in the Social Sciences?" (unpublished MS), 1953 (Box 4 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 22)
    - "Cooperation in the Social Sciences?" (unpublished TS), 1955 (Box 4 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 23)
    - "Prediction in Economics" (unpublished TS), 1958 (Box 4 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 24)
    - "Zur Ortsbestimmung der Gegenwart" (unpublished TS), 1983 (Box 4 (3-Scholarly Writings), Folder 25)
- Notes, 1964-1990; 4; 0.25 cubic ft.
  This series contains Lowe's notes on various subjects. Some are simple reading notes or chronological outlines, but most of the notes comprise a detailed intellectual diary that Lowe maintained for more than twenty-five years. These notes, which document Lowe's efforts to refine his ideas about human freedom, state planning, and technological change and were apparently created in preparation for the writing of Has Freedom a Future?, also record his conversations with colleagues and difficulties in writing the book.
  - "SILS", 1964-1986 (Box 4 (4-Notes), Folder 26)
  - "Ruminations on a New Book", 1965 (Box 4 (4-Notes), Folder 27)
  - "Explorations", 1965-1967 (Box 4 (4-Notes), Folder 28)
  - "Credo-Notes", 1966 (Box 4 (4-Notes), Folder 29)
  - "Notes on 'Ought'", 1966 (Box 4 (4-Notes), Folder 30)
  - Notes on the Jonas Letter, 1966-1979 (Box 4 (4-Notes), Folder 31)
  - "The Year 2000", 1968 (Box 4 (4-Notes), Folder 32)
  - "Atlas", 1969-1976 (Box 4 (4-Notes), Folder 33)
  - "Political Economics", 1974-1976 (Box 4 (4-Notes), Folder 34)
  - "History of H-Bomb" (c.1975) and "My Dear Paul" (1943; revised 1987), ca. 1975-1987 (Box 4 (4-Notes), Folder 35)
  - "Prometheus", 1976-1979 (Box 4 (4-Notes), Folder 36)
  - "Prometheus [Continued]", 1980-1983 (Box 4 (4-Notes), Folder 37)
  - "Some Comments on 'Generalrevision'", 1983-1984 (Box 4 (4-Notes), Folder 38)
  - Unidentified Notes, 1978 (Box 4 (4-Notes), Folder 39)
  - Notes on various subjects, probably for Has Freedom a Future?, ca. 1980 (Box 4 (4-Notes), Folder 40)
  - "Deutsche Skizze", ca. 1980 (Box 4 (4-Notes), Folder 41)
  - "Interview", 1987-1988 (Box 4 (4-Notes), Folder 42)
  - "An Attempt at Clarification", 1987-1988 (Box 4 (4-Notes), Folder 43)
  - "New Book", 1988 (Box 4 (4-Notes), Folder 44)
  - "Free Association", 1990 (Box 4 (4-Notes), Folder 45)
  - "Free Association [continued]", 1990 (Box 4 (4-Notes), Folder 46)
  - "Comments on the 'Kiel School'", Undated (Box 4 (4-Notes), Folder 47)
  - "Sehr Geerhter Becknaa" and "Main Point", Undated (Box 4 (4-Notes), Folder 48)
- Lectures and Other Course Materials, ca. 1925-1981; 5; 0.60 cubic ft.
  This series contains materials that Lowe created and maintained in connection with his teaching activities at the University of Kiel, the University of Frankfurt, Manchester University, and the New School for Social Research. Lecture notes generated while Lowe was at Manchester (among them a few lectures for the Worker's Educational Association) and the New School predominate. Also included are an outline for a political theory course he taught at the University of Kiel (1930), the syllabus (1951) for his "Theory of Capitalism" course at the New School, and reading notes he used in preparing various lectures.
  - Seminar Notes on Political Theory, ca. 1925-1933; (unpublished typescript and manuscript) (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 49)
  - Summary Outline of Theoretical Seminar (unpublished TS), 1930 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 50)
  - Lectures and Notes on Political Economics, ca. 1935-1966; (unpublished typescript and manuscript) (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 51)
  - "The Spirit of Citizenship" (unpublished MS), 1937 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 52)
  - "The Gist of English Democracy" (unpublished MS), 1938 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 53)
  - "Essay Class: Modern Political Thought" (unpublished MS), 1939 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 54)
  - " A German Looks at Baldwin" (unpublished MS), 1939 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 55)
  - "The Social Foundations of English Liberty" (unpublished MS), 1939 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 56)
  - "Faschism [sic]" (unpublished MS), 1939 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 57)
  - "War Aims" (unpublished MS), 1939 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 58)
  - "Our Attitude to Germany" (unpublished MS), 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 59)
  - "The Reform of Germany" (unpublished MS), 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 60)
  - "Social Transformation and the War" (unpublished MS), 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 61)
  - Lecture on War Aims (unpublished MS), 1940? (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 62)
  - "The National and Constitutional Problem in circa 17 Germany" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 63)
  - "German Attitude Toward Classical Economics" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 64)
  - Lectures on English Reform and Napoleon (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 65)
  - "On Freedom" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 66)
  - "Age of Reform" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 67)
  - "Prussia in C[entury] 18" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 68)
  - "Pro National Government!" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 69)
  - "The Lesson of the Ab[yssinian] Dispute" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 70)
  - "Problem und Wirtschaftstheorie" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 71)
  - "Romantic Movement [1]" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 72)
  - "Romantik" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 73)
  - "Main Points in German Romanticism" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 74)
  - "Romantic Movement [2]" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 75)
  - "Goethe" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 76)
  - "Material for Paper on Locke-Kant" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 77)
  - "Locke-Kant" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 78)
  - "German Literature of C[entury] 17" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 79)
  - "Hillmann[?] --Discussion" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 80)
  - "I.S.S. --Paper" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 81)
  - Notes on various readings, ca. 1940; (unpublished manuscript) (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 82)
  - Untitled Notes on a Paper, ca. 1940; (unpublished manuscript) (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 83)
  - "General Agenda for Seminar IV" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 84)
  - "The Rise of Agrarian Capitalism" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 85)
  - "Discussion Knights" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 86)
  - "Summary for the Paper on 'Reformation'" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 87)
  - "Summary (Reformation)" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 88)
  - "Geography Paper from Dunlop" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 89)
  - "Race" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 90)
  - "Seminar III: Oldfield" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 91)
  - "Seminar --Introduction" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 92)
  - "The German Idea of Freedom" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 93)
  - "The Spirit of English Democracy" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 94)
  - "The New Problem of the English Intelligentsia" (unpublished MS), ca. 1940 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 95)
  - "British War Economy" (unpublished MS), 1941 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 96)
  - "Economic Controls and Political Power" (unpublished MS), 1941 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 97)
  - Lectures and Notes on Classical and Modern Theories of Economic Growth, 1947-1960; (unpublished typescript and manuscript) (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 98)
  - Course Syllabus, "Theory of Capitalism" (unpublished TS), 1951 (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 99)
  - Lectures and Notes on World Economics, ca. 1955; (unpublished manuscript) (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 100)
  - Lectures and Notes on Value, Clark, Hicks, Walras, and Marx, ca. 1970-1981; (unpublished typescript and manuscript) (Box 4 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 101)
  - Lectures and Notes on Ricardo, 1971-1975 (Box 5 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 1)
  - "On the Theory of Value" (unpublished TS), 1971 (Box 5 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 2)
  - Untitled Lecture, 1973 (Box 5 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 3)
    (unpublished typescripts) and Notes (unpublished manuscripts).
  - Untitled Lecture on Marx (unpublished TS), ca. 1975 (Box 5 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 4)
  - Untitled Lecture on Marx (unpublished TS), and Flier, ca. 1975 (Box 5 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 5)
  - "'Generalization' of Political Economics" (unpublished TS), ca. 1975 (Box 5 (5-Lectures and Other Course Materials), Folder 6)
- Research Materials, 1940-1996; 6; 0.45 cubic ft.
  This series consists of published and unpublished articles, clippings, and other documents that Lowe gathered in connection with his academic research. Many of these materials consist of critical analyses of his work and were presented to him by colleagues. Others were written by faculty members at the New School for Social Research, among them Robert Heilbroner, Hans Jonas, Anwar Shaikh, and Hans Staudinger. Also included is a copy of Claus-Dieter Krohn's intellectual biography of Lowe, Der Philosophische Ökonom. Krohn, who was in possession of the materials in this collection at the time of Lowe's death, may have added the book to the collection.
  - Amendola, "The Path to a Dynamic Analysis of the 'Traverse': A. Lowe and J.R. Hicks" (unpublished TS), ca. 1980 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 7)
  - Burnshaw, "Mirages: Travel Notes in the Promised Land", ca. 1975; (unpublished typescript) (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 8)
  - Chase, "Vision, Theory Debate and the Development of Mainstream Economics" (published), 1981 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 9)
  - Feldman, "Wirtschafts- und socialpolitische Probleme der Deutschen Demobilmachtung 1918/19" (published), 1974 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 10)
  - Haass, "Adolph Lowes Vison des Wohlfahrtsstaates..." (published[?]), 1990 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 11)
  - Hacking, "Winner Take Less" (published), 1984 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 12)
  - Hagemann and Jeck, "Lowe and the Marx-Feldman-Dobb Model..." (published), 1984 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 13)
  - Hagemann and Kurz, "Balancing Freedom and Order: on Adolph Lowe's Political Economics" (unpublished TS), ca. 1990 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 14)
  - Harvey, "Professor Lowe and His Critique of Marx" (unpublished TS), ca. 1975 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 15)
  - Heilbroner, "Modern Economics as a Chapter in the History of Economic Thought" (unpublished TS), ca. 1970 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 16)
  - Jaszi, "Notes on Adolph Lowe: Toward a Science of Political Economics", 1968; (unpublished typescript) (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 17)
  - Jonas, H., "Life, Death, and the Body in the Theory of Being" (published), 1965 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 18)
  - Jonas, H., "Philosophical Reflections on Experimenting with Human Subjects (unpublished TS) and "Contemporary Problems in Science and Ethics" (published), ca. 1970 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 19)
  - Jonas, H., "Philosophical Reflections on Experimenting with Human Subjects" (published), 1969 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 20)
  - Jonas, H., "Against the Stream" (unpublished TS), 1970 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 21)
  - Jonas, H., "Das Problem des Lebens und des Liebes in der Lehre von Sein" (published), ca. 1970 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 22)
  - Jonas, H., "Philosophical Aspects of Technology" (unpublished TS), ca. 1975 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 23)
  - Jonas, H., "On the Power or Impotence of Subjectivity" (published), 1976 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 24)
  - Jonas, H., "Impotence or Power of Subjectivity" Postscript" (unpublished TS), 1977 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 25)
  - Jonas, H., "The Concept of Responsibility: An Inquiry..." (published), 1977 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 26)
  - Jonas, H., "Straddling the Boundaries of Theory and Practice: Recombinant DNA Research..." (published), 1978 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 27)
  - Jonas, H., "Reflections on Technology, Progress, and Utopia" (published), 1981 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 28)
  - Jonas, H., "Der Gottesbegriff nach Auschwitz" (unpublished TS), ca. 1985 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 29)
  - Jonas, H., "Werkzeug, Bild, und Grab vom Transanimalischen in Menschen" (unpublished TS), 1985 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 30)
  - Jonas, H., "Geist, Natur, und Schöpfung" (unpublished TS), ca. 1985 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 31)
  - Jonas, H., "Rechte, Recht, und Ethik" (unpublished TS), 1986 (Box 5 (6-Research Materials), Folder 32)